Finding Aid for Department of Biology (University of Michigan) publications, 1945-2002
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Department of Biology (University of Michigan) publications 1945-2002 1977-2000
University of Michigan. Department of Biology
1 linear foot
0230 Bimu C26 2
Publications produced by or for the Department of Biology, includes miscellaneous newsletters such as the Gnat's Eye Gnus, histories, and brochures.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The publications group was transferred from the Department of Biology (Donor No. 7328) and Professor Ed Voss (Donor No. 3263 ).
Periodic additions to the records expected.
The publications are open without restriction.
For background of this unit, please consult the history found in the University of Michigan Department of Biology manuscript finding aid immediately preceding the publications finding aid.
The Department of Biology Publications are divided into two series: Unit Publications and Student Publications.
The Unit Publications series contains printed material published specifically by the Department of Biology. These publications are defined as being widely distributed and may be published at regular intervals. They are arranged by genre of the publication.
The Unit Publications are divided into publications documenting the Department of Biology and the Department of Botany. The Department of Biology printed materials include brochures dating from 1978 to 1995 and bulletins detailing graduate studies in biology. The history "Biological Research at Michigan," first published in The Biologist, describes the Biology Department up to 1938. The Gnats Eye Gnus (.9 linear ft.) is a newsletter documenting the weekly activities of the Biology Department from 1977 to 2000. There is an almost complete run of this publication.
The Department of Botany publications include a history written circa 1953 and the newsletter U-M Botany Times which was published from 1990 to 1998.
The Student Publications series contains publications published by student groups within the Department of Biology.
The Student Publications series contains email from the Black Biology Association from 1997 to 1998.
Subjects:
University of Michigan. Dept. of Biology.; University of Michigan. Division of Biological Sciences.; University of Michigan. Dept. of Botany.; Biology--Study and teaching (Higher)--Curricula.; Gnat's eye gnus.
Contributors:
University of Michigan. Division of Biological Sciences.; University of Michigan. Dept. of Botany.
Genre Terms:
Newsletters.; Histories.; Brochures.
- Unit Publications
  - Department of Biology
    - Brochures, 1978-1995 and undated (Box 1)
    - Bulletins
      - Graduate Studies in Biological Sciences, ca. 1983 (Box 1)
      - Graduate Studies in Biology, ca. 1988-1992 (Box 1)
    - Flyers
      - Course Offerings, 1997 (Box 1)
      - Faculty Candidate Seminar, 2001-2002, 2 folders (Box 1)
      - Fall and Winter Seminar
        - 1977-1999, 4 folders (Box 1)
        - 2001 (Box 1)
    - Histories
      - "Biological Research at Michigan" in The Biologist, 1938 (Box 1)
    - Newsletters
      - Gnats Eye Gnus
        - 1977-1978 no. 1-41 (Box 1)
        - 1978-1979 no. 1-46 (Box 1)
        - 1979-1980 no. 1-49 (Box 1)
        - 1980-1981 no. 1-45 (Box 1)
        - 1981-1982 no. 1-43 (Box 1)
        - 1982-1983 no. 1-40 (Box 1)
        - 1983-1984 no. 1-41 (Box 1)
        - 1984-1985 no. 1-44 (Box 1)
        - 1985-1986 no. 1-47 (Box 1)
        - 1986-1987 no. 1-41 (Box 1)
        - 1987-1988 no. 1-39 (Box 1)
        - 1988-1989 no. 1-41 (Box 1)
        - 1989-1990 no. 1-42 (Box 1)
        - 1990-1991 no. 1-43 (Box 1)
        - 1991-1992 no. 1-45 (Box 1)
        - 1992-1993 no. 1-40 (Box 1)
        - 1993-1994 no. 1-34 (Box 1)
        - 1994-1995 no. 1-34 (Box 1)
        - 1995-1996 no. 1-35 (Box 1)
        - 1996-1997 no. 1-36 (Box 1)
        - 1997-1998 no. 1-35 (Box 1)
        - 1998-1999 no. 1-29 (Box 1)
        - 2000 no. 1-13 (Box 1)
      - Gnats Eye Gnus: Off Campus Edition, 1993-1994 and 1996-1999 (Box 1)
    - Reports
      - Annual report, 1996-1997 (Box 1)
      - Authority, Functions, Contributions, and Organization of the Division of the Biological Sciences, 1962 (Box 1)
      - Laboratory of Vertebrate Biology, 1945, 1949 (Box 1)
      - Space report, Division of Biological Sciences, 1956 (Box 1)
      - University Owned Lands Available to Biologists, 1984 (Box 1)
  - Department of Botany
    - Histories, ca. 1953 (Box 1)
    - Newsletter
      - U-M Botany Times
        - 1990, 1992-1995, 1997-1998 (Box 1)
- Student Publications
  - Black Biology Association
    - Email, 1997-1998